Victor A. Lora

(201) 289-1355 ♦ victor@victorlora.net ♦ github.com/victorlora ♦ /in/victorlora95 ♦ victorlora.net

An upcoming graduate offering a strong academic background in Computer Science and Mathematics combined with excellent internship experience as a Software Developer and NOC Engineer. Strong skills in a range of computer systems, languages, tools and testing methodologies. Successful in both team and self-directed settings. Multi-lingual speaking English, Italian and Spanish. Academic career distinguished by attaining Dean's List every semester and a 3.8/4.0 GPA.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Muhlenberg College, Allentown, PA 2017

Relevant Coursework: Computer Organization, Databases, Data Structures & Algorithms, Natural Language

Processing, Programming Languages, Software Engineering, Web Development

HIGHLIGHTS

Software Development

Object Oriented Design

Debugging

Algorithms

Leadership

Databases

Communication

Problem Resolution

Customer Relations

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End Coding: HTML5: CSS: JavaScript

Back-End Coding: Java; Python; SQL; PHP; Swift; C++

Tools & Frameworks: Eclipse; Git; Linux; Maven; MySQL; OSX; Postgres; Redmine; Smart GWT; Spring; Tomcat

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SAUCON TECHNOLOGIES, Bethlehem, PA, Software Developer Intern

2015-Present

- Interfaced with customers and project managers to design, develop, test and deploy both the server and client side code for a web-based, flexible vehicle maintenance system, which allows motor coach companies to track maintenance cycles, work orders, parts, labor, budgets and more.
- Designed and developed an inventory system that tracks purchase orders, inventory check-ins/outs via QR Codes, tracks warranties on different parts, and interfaces with a vehicle maintenance system.
- Create, update, and debug dynamic web portal modules and applications based on customer specifications adhering to monthly release cycles.

NU-AGE MANAGED SERVICES, Pearl River, NY, NOC Engineer Intern

2014-2015

- Effectively resolved functional and technical issues by troubleshooting and diagnosing hardware, software and network issues on-site, over the phone, and by email.
- Documented tickets/resolutions as well as system configurations and technical procedures.
- Increased response time by consolidating three separate document databases into a single, wellorganized FileMaker database

AWARDS & HONORS

Presidential Merit Scholarship, 2013 - Present
The Dr. Anthony J. Marino Jr. Award in Computing Science, 2016
Third Place - PACISE Programming Competition, 2016

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Emerging Leaders Program Member/Mentor, inducted 2013 Cardinal Key Society Member, inducted 2013 Peer Tutor, 2015 - Present